Guide to the Robert T. Jones Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Aeronautical Files, Series I
  - Oshkosh airfoils (1 of 2), 1984 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Oshkosh airfoils (2 of 2), 1983-84 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Oswatitsch, K. and K. Wieghardt. Ludwing Prandtl and his Kaiser-Wilhelm-Institut. Annual Review Fluid Mechanics 1987 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Owl Feather Society Tenth Anniversary, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Parachute (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Patent: application for single wing supersonic aircraft (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Patent: beveled T. E., 1943-66 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Patent: Dual-Fuselage Aircraft Having Yawable Wing and Horizontal Stabilizer; includes letter from Wayne Medsker, 1970-73 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Patent: William E. Bell for aeroplanes with v-shaped wing, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Patents: VTOL (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Perry, Byrne. The Effect of Aspect Ratio on the Lift of Flat Planing Surfaces. ONR Report, Sept. 1952 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Phillips, J. D. - articles, 1985-90 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Phillips, William H. "Recollections of Langley in the Forties" (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographs and illustrations - airplanes, images of Mars, space (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photographs - models (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Physics News - proposed article, 1986-87 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - "Physics of flight in the atmosphere" - draft (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Pinsky, J. "Adronia" [short story] (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Pitch stability (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Pitching motion: alpha control (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Pobjoy racer - articles and drawings (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Pobjoy racer - correspondence, 1938-1997 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Pobjoy racer - photograph (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Poinsot motion - correspondence, 1959-60 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Poinsot motion - notes (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Popular Science award for oblique wing design (includes photo of oblique wing AD-1 in flight over Mojave Desert), 1990-93 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - "Possibilities of Efficient High-Speed Transport Airplanes." Conference on High-Speed Aeronautics, January 1955 - mimeo and published versions of Jones'paper (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Princeton Press, correspondence (1 of 2), 1989-94 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Princeton Press, correspondence (2 of 2), 1988-95 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Programs: Mag. cards (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Propeller theory - notebook (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Propeller theory - notes (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Propellers: gear shift and others - notes; includes fragments from 2 letters to Jones from E. Larrabee, 1988, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Propellers: NACA reports [originally with box 4, fol 10], 1931-1957 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Propellers - noise reduction (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Properties of ellipses - NACA memoranda, 1940-41 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Properties of ellipses - notebook (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Properties of ellipses - notes (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Pterodactyl: notes (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Pterodactyl: papers, materials from Quetzalcoatlus Northropi workshop, and 1 photograph of ultra-light plane, 1981-86 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Pulliam, T. H. and H. Lomax. Simulation of Three-Dimensional Compressible Viscous Flow on the Illiac IV Computer. 17th Aerospace Sciences Meeting, January 1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Quaternions - articles, 1974-89 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Quaternions I - notes from Hamilton's "Elements" (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Range (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Relativistic Kinematics: slides of figures for Jones'article and "Notes on the Clock Paradox" by B. M. Oliver, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Relativity - articles, 1941-1983 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Relativity (J. Franklin Institute paper) - notes and typescript of article (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Remote Controlled Models (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Riparbelli, C. Two reprints, 1953-54 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Rocket: vertical ascent range (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Rockets, space: notes, articles, 1959-79 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Rott, Nicholas. Four reprints, 1951-59 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Royal Aeronautical Society: correspondence re publication of Jones'work and copies of RAS publications, 1987-91 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Rubesin, Morris W. Numerical Turbulence Modeling. Ames Research Center, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Rutan, Burt - articles (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Safety of slow aircraft: correspondance, drawings, typescript, and printed version of "Safety of Slow Flying Aircraft,", 1983-84 and undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Scale model, citation, etc. - notes (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Schade, Th. Theorie der schwingenden kreisformigen Tragflache auf potentialtheoretischer Grundlage. April 1940 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Schmitz, F. W. Aerodynamics of the Model Airplane. Part I Airfoil Measurements. 1941, translated from the German in 1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Schwarz, L. Two reprints (in German), 1940 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Science (magazine) - misc. articles, 1970-79 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Science: miscellaneous articles from NATURE and other sources, 1975-84 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Sears, W. R. Some Remarks about Flow Past Bodies. Reviews of Modern Physics, Oct. 1960 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Sears lecture: Cornell and U. of Arizona - correspondence, notes, text, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Seebass, A. R. - articles (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Side force - notes, drawings (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Sixty-three degree wing drag - notes, figures, photos of model, and typescript "Characteristics of an airplane with a large angle of sweepback,", 1947 and undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Slender wing theory - articles, 1946, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Small airplanes - articles (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Small airplanes - NACA Technical Memorandum #326, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Smith, J. H. B. Life/Drag Ratios of Optimised Slewed Elliptic Wings at Supersonic Speeds, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "Some considerations in the Design of Transport Aircraft," Turnbull Lecture, typescript, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Sonic boom - articles about and letter from William Shurcliff, 1945, 1969-71 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Sound Barrier and the Light Barrier," drafts (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - "Sound Barrier and the Light Barrier," figures and correspondence, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Space photographs (100 and 200 inch) (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Space structures - artielces, notes, correspondence, 1958-71 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - SST performance - notebook (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Stability climax programs (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Stability derivatives (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Stability low speed (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Standard JN-4 plane - handbooks (1918, 1925), notes, articles, correspondence, 1972-84 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Standard JN-4 plane - photographs (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Stanford classes, 1994, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Stanford notes (1) (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Stanford notes (2) (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Stanford viewgraphs; includes photo of models in wind tunnels (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Subsonic aerodynamics - typescript (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Supersonic Air Transportation - drafts (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Supersonic Flying Wing - drafts (1 0f 2) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - "Supersonic Flying Wing," - drafts (2 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Supersonic flying wing - old figures and text (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Supersonic fuselages - notes (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Sutton, Emmett A. Measurement of the Dissociation Rates of Hydrogen and Deuterium. Journal of Chemical Physics, June 1962 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Swanson, Margaret, "Effects of a Boundary Layer on the Pitching Moments and Hinge Moments of an Airfoil," NACA, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Tachyons - articles, 1962-75 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Tailless airplanes - notes, typescript of "Dynamics of Ultrlight Aircraft - comparative longitudinal stability of tailless gliders," 1977 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Tailless airplanes, Stability of - articles, 1930-78 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Tamada, Ko. Two reprints, 1962 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Taylor, G. I. Note on the Connection between the Lift on an Aerofoil in a Wind and the Circulation Round it. 1924 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Taylor monoplane - plans (n.d.) and letter from Mrs. John F. Taylor, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Thickness drag, ellipse - notes, graphs, etc., 1971-91 and undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Tip vortices: articles, notes, correspondence, 1918-1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Tsien, Hsue-Shnen, "Superaerodynamics, mechanics of Rarefied Gases," Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, December 1946 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Tsuge, Shunichi: correspondence and papers, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Turbojet characteristics - figures, notes, etc. (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Turbojet characteristics - sources (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Turbulence modeling - articles (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Turbulence modeling - notes (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Turcotte, D. L. and J. M. Lyons. A Periodic Boundary-Layer Flow in Magnetohydrodynamcis. Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Turn meter (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Ulam, Stanislaw, "On the Possibility of Extracting Energy from Granitational Systems by Navigating Space Vehicles," 1958 [photographic reproduction] (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Unsteady lift: notes (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Unsteady lift: Y. Nakamura letter and paper, 1991-92 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - "Use of Conical and Cylindrical Fields in Supersonic Wing Theory,", 1948 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Useful L/D's (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Viscous flow (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Vortex drag - wing weight (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Vortex generators, sources, notes, memorandum, 1951-78 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Voyager (aircraft), 1987 and undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Weick, Fred E. Propeller Design: A Simple System Based on Model Propeller Test Data - III. NACA Technical Note No. 237 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Windmills, notes and sources (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Wing dynamics - notebook (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Wing Flapping with Minimum Energy - text, article, correspondence, 1980 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Wing leveler - articles, reports (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Wing leveler - notes and sources (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Wing leveler: turn rate (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - WING THEORY, chap. 7-8 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - WING THEORY, draft of chapters 9-10 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - WING THEORY, chap. 9-10 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - WING THEORY, Data for text (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - WING THEORY, Disc titles; references (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - WING THEORY, Discarded text (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - WING THEORY, dust jacket; text of something in Chinese (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - WING THEORY, errors in text (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - WING THEORY, Figure captions, page numbers, permissions (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - WING THEORY, Typeset accounts (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Wing weights (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Winglet results (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Winglets - British reports, 1954-56 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - XYXY delta Airfoil theory (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Aeronautical Files: Swept Wing Original Papers, Series II
  - "The Shaping of Wings to Minimize the Formation of Shock Waves" - typescript and figures, 1945 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Record of invention, Apr. 10, 1946, and list of claims (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and forms re patent application, 1945-46, 1958 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Copies of patents for swept-wing forms to W. E. Bell, 1933, and A. H. G. Fokker, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Color negative of delta-wing drawing (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Binder containing color xeroxes of materials in folders 5 through 8, with explanatory letter by Harriet Jones, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Publications and Reprints, Series III
  - 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    "Calculation of the Motion of an Airplane Under the Influence of Irregular Disturbances," Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, October 1936.
    "The Reduction of Aileron Operating Force by Differential Linkage," NACA Technical Note No. 586, Dec. 1936.
    "Study of the Two-Control Operation of an Airplane," NACA Report No. 579, 1936.
    "The Effect of Lateral Controls in Producing Motion of an Airplane as Computed from Wind-Tunnel Data," NACA Report 570, 1937.
  - 1938-1939 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    "Operational Treatment of the Nonuniform-Lift Theory in Airplane Dynamcis," NACA Technical Note No. 667, Oct. 1938 (3 cc).
    "Theoretical Stability and Control Characteristics of Wings with Various Amounts of Taper and Twist," NACA Report No. 635.
    "The Unsteady Lift of a Finite Wing," NACA Technical Note No. 682, Jan. 1939.
  - 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    "Transient Effects of the Wing Wake on the Horizontal Tail," NACA Technical Note No. 771, Aug. 1940 (2 cc).
    "Correction of the Lifting-Line Theory for the Effect of the Chord," NACA Technical Note No. 817, July 1941 (original and annotated photocopy).
    "Notes on the Stability and Control of Tailless Airplanes," NACA Technical Note No. 837, 1941 (photocopy).
  - 1942-1943 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    "Wind-Tunnel Investigation of Control-Surface Characteristics V - The Use of a Beveled Trailing Edge to Reduce the Hinge Moment of a Control Surface," NACA Report, March 1942.
    "Determination of Optimum Plan Forms for Control Surfaces," NACA Report No. 731, 1942.
    "Theory and Preliminary Flight Tests of an All-Movable Vertical Tail surface," NACA Report, Jan. 1943.
  - 1946 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    "Properties of Los-Aspect-Ration Pointed Wings at Speeds below and above the Speed of Sound," NACA Technical Note No. 1032, Mar. 1946 (1 complete and 1 partial copy).
    "Wing Plan Forms for High-Speed Flight," NACA Technical Note No. 1033, Mar. 1946.
    "Thin Oblique Airfoils at Supersonic Speed," NACA Technical Note No. 1107, Sept. 1946.
  - 1947 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    "Subsonic Flow Over Thin Oblique Airfoils at Zero Lift," NACA Technical Note No. 1340, June 1947.
    "Estimated Lift-Drag Ratios at Supersonic Speed," NACA Technical Note No. 1350, July 1947.
    "Effects of Sweepback on Boundary Layer and Separation," NACA Technical Note No. 1402, July 1947.
    "Wing Plan Forms for High-Speed Flight," NACA Report No. 863, 1947 (4 cc).
  - 1949 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    "A Method for Predicting the Stability in Roll of Automaticlly Controlled Aircraft Based on the Experimental Determination of the Characteristic of an Automatic Pilot," NACA Technical Note 1901, June 1949.
    "Properties of Los-Aspect-Ration Pointed Wings at Speeds below and above the Speed of Sound," Report No. 835 (Reissue of 1946 technical note 1032), 1949.
  - 1950-1952 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    "The Spanwise Distribution of Lift for Minimum Induced Drage of Wings Having a Given Lift and a Given Bending Moment," NACA Technical Note 2249, December 1950.
    "The Minimum Drag of Thin Wings in Frictionless Flow," Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, Feb. 1951.
    "Theoretical Determination of the Minimum Drage of Airfoils at Supersonic Speeds," Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, Dec. 1952.
  - 1956-59 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    "Times for Interplanetary Trips," Jet Propulsion, Feb. 1956.
    "Minimum Wave Drag for Arbetrary Arrangements of Wings and Bodies," NACA Technical Note 3530, Feb. 1956.
    "Some Recent Developments in the Aerodynamics of Wings for High Speeds," Zeitschrift fur Flugwissenschaften, Aug. 1956.
    "Theory of Wing-Body Drag at Supersonic Speeds," NACA Report 1284, 1956.
    "Compressibility Rule for Drag of Airfoil Noses," Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences, March 1958.
    "The Kutta Condition and the Condition for Minimum Drag," Journal of the Aero/Space Sciences, June 1959.
  - 1960-1965 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    "Extending the Lorentz Transformation by Characteristic Coordinates," American Journal of Physics, Feb. 1960.
    "Analysis of Accelerated Motion in the Theory of Relativity," Nature, June 4, 1960.
    "Conformal Coordinates Associated with Uniformly Accelerated Motion," American Journal of Physics, Feb. 1961.
    "Conformal Coordinates Associated with Space-Like Motions," Journal of the Franklin Institute, Jan. 1963.
    "Three-Dimensional Wings of Minimum Pressure Drag (Chapter 8 of Theory of Optimum Aerodynamic Shapes)," Academic Press, 1965.
  - 1965-1972 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    "Motions of a Liquid in a Pulsating Bulb with Application to Problems of Blood Flow," Avco Everett Research Laboratory, Research Report 237, Dec. 1965.
    "Application of Fluid Dynamcis to Circulatory Assist Devices," AIAA Third Annual Meeting, Dec. 1966.
    "Elementary Theory of Synchronous Arterio-Arterial Blood Pumps," 20th Annual Conference on Engineering in Medicine and Biology, Nov. 1967.
    "Elementary Theory of Synchronous Arterio-Arterial Blood Pumps," Med. & biol. Engng, Vol. 6, pp. 303-308,, 1968.
    "Blood Flow," Annual Review of Fluid Mechanics, Vol. 1, 1969.
    "Motions of a Liquid in a Pulsating Bulb with Application to Problems of Blood Flow," Med. & biol. Engng, Vol. 8, 1970.
    "Fluid Dynamcis of Heart Assist Devices, from Biomechanics: Its Foundations and Objectives," Prentice-Hall, 1972.
  - 1972-1974 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    "Reduction of Wave Drag by Antisymmetric Arrangement of Wings and Bodies," AIAA Journal, Feb. 1972.
    "New Design Goals and a New Shape for the SST," Astronautics & Aeronautics, Dec. 1972.
    "Transonic-Transport Wings - Oblique or Swept?," Astronautics & Aeronautics, Jan. 1974.
    "Oblique-wing Aircraft Appear Best for Transonic Flight Operations," ICAO Bulletin, Feb. 1974.
    "Aircraft Design for Flight Below the sonic Boom Speed Limit," Canadian Aeronautics and Space Journal, May 1974.
  - 1973 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    "Experimental Investigation of Three Oblique-Wing and Body Cominatons at Mach Numbers Between 0.60 and 1.40," NASA Technical Memorandum, April 1973.
  - 1975 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    "Transonic Wind-Tunnel Tests of an F-8 Airplane Model Equipped with 12- and 14-Percent-Thick Oblique Wings," NASA Tech. Memorandum, October 1975.
    "Some Considerations in the Design of Transport Aircraft," Canadian Aeronautics and Space Journal, Nov. 1975.
  - 1976 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    "Transonic Lateral and Longitudinal Control Characteristics of an F-8 Airplane Model Equipped with an Oblique Wing," NASA Technical Memorandum, March 1976.
  - 1976-1978 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    "Aeroelastic Stability and Control of an Oblique Wing: Wind Tunnel Experiments," Journal of Aircraft, Oct. 1976.
    "Dynamics of Ultralight Aircraft - Motion in Vertical Gusts," NASA Technical Memorandum, Apr. 1977.
    "Dynamics of Ultralight Aircraft - Dive Recovery of Hang Gliders," NASA Technical Memorandum, May 1977.
    "The Oblique Wing - Aircraft Design for Transonic and Low Supersonic Speeds," Acta Astronautica, Vol. 4, pp. 99-109, 1977.
    "Recollections from an Earlier Period in American Aeronautics," Annual Review of Fluid Mechanincs (9:1-11), 1977.
    "Highlights from the History of Airfoil Development," Sport Aviation, June 1978.
  - 1980-1982 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    "Effect of Winglets on the Induced Drag of Ideal Wing Shapes," NASA Technical Memorandum, Sept. 1980.
    "Some Observations on Supersonic Wing Design", 1980.
    "The Idea of Progress," Astronautics & Aeronautics, May 1981.
    "Relativistic Kinematics for Motion Faster than Light," NASA Technical Memorandum, Feb. 1982.
    "Relativistic Kinematics for Motion Faster than Light," Journal of the British Interplanetary Society, Nov. 1982.
  - 1984-1991 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    "Safety of Slow Flying Aircraft," Sport Aviation, Mar. 1984.
    "Improving the Efficiency of Smaller Transport Aircraft," NASA Technical Memorandum, July 1984.
    "Flying-Wing SST for the Pacific," Aerospace America, Nov. 1986.
    "The MInimum Drag of Thin Wings at Supersonic Speed According to Kogan's Theory," Theoretical and Computational Fluid Dynamics, 1: 97-103, (1989).
    "Technical Note: The Flying Wing Supersonic Transport, " The Aeronautical Journal of the Royal Aeronautical Society, Mar. 1991.
  - 1990 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    "Wing Theory" (Japanese edition).
- Telescopes and Optics, Series IV
  - Avco optics (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Cassegrain: Astigmatism, coma (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Diffraction: apodization (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Diffraction central obstruction (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Diffraction - notebook (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Eight inch camera (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Hubble telescope (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Image spread functions (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Lenses - notebooks (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Lenses - notes, 1968 and n.d. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Mak-cassegrain (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Maksutov lens; Barlow (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Mirrors/Lenses - notes (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Photometry (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Programs - optics (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Schmidt, Ritchey-Chretian (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Six inch cassegrain telescope (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Space telescope - notes (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Telescopes - articles by Jones (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Telescopes - notebook (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Telescopes - notebook (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Telescopes - notes (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Telescopes - misc. notes (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Telescopes - photographs (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Thin Bouwers lens color (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Vega (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Vega [includes photographs] (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Vega: 6 in., F/4 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Vega: 8-inch (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Vega gratings (photographs) (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Wide angle lens (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Wide angle lens - article (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Violins and Acoustics, Series V
  - Acoustic experiments (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Acoustic experiments with the violin - Jones'article (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Acoustic experiments with the violin (paper), 1995-97 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Acoustics of the violin (slides, charts, partial text), 1989 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Articles on RTJ as violin maker (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Catcut Acoustical Society Newsletter, #19-28, (1973-77) (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Catcut Acoustical Society Newsletter, #29-41, (1978-84) (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Catcut Acoustical Society, CAS Journal, 1984-86 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Catcut Acoustical Society, CAS Journal, 1996-97 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Catcut Acoustical Society - correspondence, index, and miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Dimensions (violins) (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Experiments [same graphs as frequency response], 1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Frequency response (graphs), 1985-90 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Frequency response - experiments (1) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Frequency response - experiments (2) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Frequency response (Strad., Guar., etc.) (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Frequency response - test results RTJ (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Guitar - frequency graph and images (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Loudspeakers (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Old violins - novel designs (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - violins, appraisals (includes some postcard correspondence) (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Photographs - violins, experimental setup (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Physics of Music, readings from Scientic American, (1978) (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Relations between the vibration pattern and the sound field of a violin - text, charts, source materials (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Relations between the vibration pattern and the sound field of a violin, with correspondence, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Smith, J. O. Techniques for digital filter design and system identificaton with application to the violin. CCRMA, Dept. of Music, S.U., June 1983 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Sound level (Cane violin); filter (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Sources on violins (Meinel, Saunders, Mockel) (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Speaker response, Klipsch horn cross-over (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Turntable, tape recorder pick-ups (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Viola (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Violin acoustics - other (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Violin acoustics - RTJ (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Violin acoustics - Strad. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Violin addresses (Box 33, Folder 5)